<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>DevOps on d47zm3</title>
    <link>https://d47zm3.me/resources/devops/</link>
    <description>Recent content in DevOps on d47zm3</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://d47zm3.me/resources/devops/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS</title>
      <link>https://d47zm3.me/resources/devops/aws/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d47zm3.me/resources/devops/aws/</guid>
      <description> Grant acces to your S3 bucket for other AWS account. { &amp;#34;Id&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;Policy1519815897918&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;Version&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;2012-10-17&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;Statement&amp;#34;: [ { &amp;#34;Sid&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;Stmt1519815367664&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;Action&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;s3:*&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;Effect&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;Allow&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;Resource&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;arn:aws:s3:::private-multimedia/*&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;Principal&amp;#34;: { &amp;#34;CanonicalUser&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;01b2fc158a01666bfb1b56da6ad958d3c6fe8702540de3af517106f9aca37766&amp;#34; } } ] }</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes</title>
      <link>https://d47zm3.me/resources/devops/kubernetes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d47zm3.me/resources/devops/kubernetes/</guid>
      <description>Everything related to Kubernetes.
Interesting Sites  Official Docs - best resource for Kubernetes
 Kubedex - great blog with posts on Kubernetes subjects, comparing solutions etc.
 Inguardians - blog from redteamers about hacking &amp;amp; securing kubernetes
 50 useful Kubernetes tools
 Toolnetes - useful Kubernetes tools, tested in battle
  Customization, Service Mesh, gRPC (more advanced stuff) Kustomization  Kustomize: Deploy Your App with Template Free YAML - Ryan Cox, Lyft</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linux Network Monitoring Tools</title>
      <link>https://d47zm3.me/resources/devops/linux-network-monitoring-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d47zm3.me/resources/devops/linux-network-monitoring-tools/</guid>
      <description>Original Link: https://haydenjames.io/linux-networking-commands-scripts/
 arpwatch – ethernet activity monitor. bmon – bandwidth monitor and rate estimator. bwm-ng – live network bandwidth monitor. curl – transferring data with urls. darkstat – captures network traffic, usage statistics. dhclient – dynamic host configuration protocol client dig – query dns servers for information. dstat – replacement for vmstat, iostat, mpstat, netstat and ifstat. ethtool – utility for controlling network drivers and hardware. ftp – simplest file transfer protocol.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PKI</title>
      <link>https://d47zm3.me/resources/devops/pki/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d47zm3.me/resources/devops/pki/</guid>
      <description>Based on great article here, just my notes and highlighted fragments. Taken from article https://smallstep.com/blog/everything-pki.html
TLDR: The goal of certificates and PKI is to bind names to public keys.
Terms like entity, identity, identifier, name, subscriber, end entity, certificate authority, root certificates, leaf certificates (these belong to end entities), relying party ( a certificate user that verifies and trusts certificates issued by a CA )
A message authentication code (MAC) is a bit of data that’s used to verify which entity sent a message, and to ensure that a message hasn’t been modified.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tools</title>
      <link>https://d47zm3.me/resources/devops/tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d47zm3.me/resources/devops/tools/</guid>
      <description>Generic page for interesting, useful tools, not really fitting into other category:
 mkcert - local TLS certificates with green lock via your own CA installed on system  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tricks</title>
      <link>https://d47zm3.me/resources/devops/tricks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d47zm3.me/resources/devops/tricks/</guid>
      <description>Miscellaneous tricks that did not made it into other categories.
Find Real IPs behind CloudFlare I&amp;rsquo;m using CrimeFlare for it.
Expose Local Server behind NAT via public VPS # run from machine which has access to private site ssh -R 8443:private-site:443 user@public_vps Now add new /etc/hosts entry reflecting vhost of private website pointing to public VPS IP and access it via https://private-site:8443/
Debugging on Container OS using Docker Actually it boils down to running Docker container which shares namespaces with host, installing tools there and debugging.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wordpress</title>
      <link>https://d47zm3.me/resources/devops/wordpress/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d47zm3.me/resources/devops/wordpress/</guid>
      <description>Update mutli-site primary URL In order to update main blog URL update these tables in database:
wp_options: change “siteurl” and “home” to the new URL (http://blog/) wp_sitemeta: there’s a “siteurl” field you’ll need to change here wp_site: change the only value here to your new domain wp_blogs: each subsite will have an entry here, you’ll need to update the domain column for each row Also, update wp-config.php file:
define( &amp;#39;DOMAIN_CURRENT_SITE&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;newblog.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>