<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>d47zm3</title>
    <link>https://d47zm3.me/</link>
    <description>Recent content on d47zm3</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Mar 2021 12:44:05 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://d47zm3.me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Personal Cybersecurity Checklist</title>
      <link>https://d47zm3.me/resources/personal-cybersecurity-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Mar 2021 12:44:05 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d47zm3.me/resources/personal-cybersecurity-list/</guid>
      <description> HOW TO STAY SECURE IN DANGEROUS TIMES (2021 EDITION) This guide has few areas, where one can improve his security standards.
HUMAN FACTOR each protection can be broken by human and cause of human mistake verify who are you talking to, callback to your bank to check if it&amp;rsquo;s their employee asking suspicious questions your friend on Facebook needs some money urgently, call his mobile and confirm it your real inbox can also be a target of attack, someone can try to trick you into some payment end-user education is a must in your company VPN can make tracking you harder, assuming provider itself is not some malicious actor allows to bypass restrictions like geographic or law ones if you&amp;rsquo;re using hotspot, encrypts your traffic so other cannot spy on you in this public network do not trust completely VPN providers, they aren&amp;rsquo;t always honest about &amp;ldquo;zero logs policy&amp;rdquo; and can be hacked as well best bet is to go with your own VPN and don&amp;rsquo;t store logs there, great tool for it is algo for shady stuff, you can always rent VPS with BitCoins and provision it with your VPN&amp;hellip; </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workspace Environment</title>
      <link>https://d47zm3.me/resources/workspace-environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Mar 2021 12:42:47 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d47zm3.me/resources/workspace-environment/</guid>
      <description>Will write about my workspace, tools, terminal and so on.
CLI Applications That You Should Know!
usql - is a universal command-line interface for PostgreSQL, MySQL, Oracle Database, SQLite3, Microsoft SQL Server, and many other databases including NoSQL and non-relational databases! exa - exa is a modern replacement for the venerable file-listing command-line program ls that ships with Unix and Linux operating systems, giving it more features and better defaults </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://d47zm3.me/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d47zm3.me/about/</guid>
      <description>Name: Damian
Age: 30
Job: DevOps Engineer
Certifications:
Offensive Security Certified Professional Certified Kubernetes Administrator Certified Kubernetes Security Specialist Google Cloud Associate Engineer AWS Certified Solutions Architect AWS Certified Security - Specialty </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bookmarks</title>
      <link>https://d47zm3.me/bookmarks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d47zm3.me/bookmarks/</guid>
      <description>DevOps:
DevOps Newsletters DevOps README Oh Shit, Git! Beginners Guide To Git Bisect HashiCorp Learn Technology Radar How to do a Code Review? HTOP Explained Project Awesome Kubernetes:
Kubernetes README ClusterAPI Network Policy Editor for Kubernetes Kubernetes Failure Stories The Kubernetes Learning Resources List 33+ Kubernetes Security Tools Kube Academy GKE - Hardening Your&amp;rsquo;s Cluster Security Deep Dive into Real-World Kubernetes Threats AWS:
AWS Endgame Whitepapers &amp;amp; Guides AWS Well-Architected Labs Google Cloud:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linkbase</title>
      <link>https://d47zm3.me/linkbase/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d47zm3.me/linkbase/</guid>
      <description>31.03.2023 Up your cloud game: 3 CTOs about Eureka moments in cloud development in 60 minutes KALI PURPLE - LEVELING THE PLAYING FIELD BlueHat 2023 Collection and Roadmap for everyone who wants DevSecOps Nosey Parker is a command-line program that finds secrets and sensitive information in textual data and Git history Temporary policy exceptions in Kubernetes with Kyverno Security Certification Roadmap Create a Console Session from IAM Credentials Vault 1.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
