<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>securi(tty)</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on securi(tty)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 08:40:18 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 08:40:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/</guid>
      <description>This is where my projects will be listed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DIP</title>
      <link>/post/dip/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 08:33:20 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/dip/</guid>
      <description>Changed my mind to make DIP instead of doing presentation during the Hack Day for workshops (which is still valid idea). This project is named after DevSecOps In A Pill, basically shell wrapper to include in development pipeline that for now has three basic functions:
 scan remote web target for vulnerabilities and misconfigurations
look for vulnerable dependencies used in project (OWASP Dependency Check)
search for sensitive exposed secrets in git repositories</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DVNA</title>
      <link>/post/dvna/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2018 09:53:23 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/dvna/</guid>
      <description>As a project for upcoming company&amp;rsquo;s internal hackday I chose to make workshops for secure coding in JavaScript, based on OWASP TOP 10 and Damn Vulnerable NodeJS Application. While I&amp;rsquo;m no coder by myself, I thought I might prepare as much I can from security perspective and use some feeback from more knowledgeable collegue in terms of code itself. The idea came when I stumbled upon &amp;ldquo;solution&amp;rdquo; book to DVNA itself from AppSeco.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cheatsheets</title>
      <link>/cheatsheets/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 20:15:35 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cheatsheets/</guid>
      <description>XSS
SQLi</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bookmarks</title>
      <link>/bookmarks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2018 18:24:10 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/bookmarks/</guid>
      <description>A collection of interesting links/repositories I found around web.
exploit writing corelan tutorials
linux (x86) exploit development series
learning exploitation with offensive computer security 2.0
modern binary exploitation
reverse engineering 101
stack buffer overflows: linux - chapter 1
smashing the stack for fun and profit
courses and labs labs for the computer and network security class
sans cyber aces
pentest training
hacking lab
learn burp suite
books the best security books to have in your library</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2018 10:04:43 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Name: Damian
Age: 27
Job: DevOps Engineer
Interests:  Psychology DIY Cooking IT (Security, System Administration, Reverse Engineering, Networks)  Accomplishments:  Offensive Security Certified Professional CTF Winner @ x33fcon 2018

I treat people same way they treat me, most important thing in my life is to stay true to myself. I never give up, I do not tolerate half measures, I know what I do, what else do you want to know?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello Infosec!</title>
      <link>/post/first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2018 10:00:42 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/first-post/</guid>
      <description>Trying to keep up with infosec, saving all valuable knowledge&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>